# Hannah McCullough

Phoenix, AZ | (602) 903-0852 | mccullough.hannah@outlook.com | Portfolio | LinkedIn | GitHub

### **SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

Innovative full-stack web developer with skills in building applications with a user-experience approach by utilizing Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, SQL databases, and RESTful API architecture. With a customer-service, management, and athletic background, I bring strong skills in client relations, collaboration, and leadership.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

JavaScript, React, Ruby on Rails, HTML, CSS, Postgres, SQLite, Git, WordPress

#### **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

### Housd, GitHub

Home maintenance checklist and service booking application designed with dual-user types for homeowners and service providers

- Modeled custom database schema and REST API with Active Record, Postgres, and Rails
- Created two different dashboards with routing based on user login information determining user's profile type
- Utilized Auth and bcrypt to authenticate user login and authorize user functionality based on user type

# Strength Trainer, GitHub

Strength training application tracker equipped with organizational workout logging and data calculations based on user input

- Developed Rails API and Postgres back end with endpoints for users and their workouts
- User interface implemented with JavaScript/React, reactstrap, and CSS
- Authenticated users at login by encrypting identifying account information via Auth and bcrypt

## Coffee Me Recipes, GitHub: Frontend | Backend

SPA to get and share coffee recipes with search and filtering tools and the capability to post new recipes

- Engineered back end using Active Record and Rails
- Implemented modern front end with JavaScript/React, Material UI, and CSS
- Designed layouts and components to provide a seamless user experience while navigating the application

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

 Freelance
 Phoenix, AZ

 Web & Graphic Designer
 03/2018 – 01/2021

Designed web sites for small businesses in the Phoenix area with enhanced UI/UX, resulting in increased traffic and leads

• Designed and created menus, flyers, digital catalogs, social media content, and logos using Adobe Photoshop

USAA Phoenix, AZ

Senior Insurance Professional 09/2018 – 11/2021

- Served as a department facilitator in the Pulse initiative by communicating employee feedback and innovation to executives
- Regularly facilitated team meetings, which resulted in an overall increase in team metrics

## Zappone's Italian Bistro/Z Catering

Phoenix, AZ

Manager/Marketing Coordinator

09/2014 - 09/2018

- Implemented modern marketing techniques, resulting in a sales increase of 25%
- Managed catering teams ranging from 3-8 employees, ensuring prompt and organized professional services

# **EDUCATION**

Scottsdale Community College

01/2018 – 12/2022 Associate in Applied Science Web Development Flatiron School

11/2021 – 03/2022 Full-Stack Web Development Scottsdale Community College

08/2018 – 12/2020 Associate in Applied Science Web Design Saint Francis University/ Lake Erie College 08/2010 – 05/2014 Bachelor of Arts Psychology

Athlete